(upbeat music)
- Well, hello everyone
and welcome to English Pie.
My name's Erica and I'm Marco.
So Marco, how are you doing today?
- I'm doing great and
I'm really looking forward
to our lesson because we're
going to the eye doctor today.
- Okay, so we've got an elementary lesson
about going to the eye doctor.
- Yes.
- Well, let's get started then
with our vocabulary preview.
- Very cabaret-y preview.
We have three words today
in our vocabulary preview.
All three words come from our dialogue.
Our first word is struggle,
struggles, struggle, struggle.
So Marco, when I struggle to do
something, what does that mean?
- It means it's difficult.
It means that you have a hard time
so you can't really do it very quickly.
- So what you have to try really hard.
- You have to try really hard.
- Yeah, to do something
that's difficult, yes.
Okay, our next word
is blurry, blurry, blurry.
Blurry, B-L-U-R-R-Y.
- Blurry, whenever something is
blurry, you can't really see it well.
- It's not clear, right?
- That's right, everything will be blurry.
- Okay, and our final word
is prescription, prescription.
Often when you go to the doctor
and you need some medicine,
he writes out a prescription.
- Right, a little paper
that says all the medicine
that you need, and then you
can go to the drugstore and buy it.
- Exactly.
- Okay, so those three words
you'll hear in today's dialogue,
and I think it's time we
listen to the dialogue.
(upbeat music)
- Hello Arthur, what
seems to be the problem?
- Very dark.
- We're all, I think I might need glasses.
I'm getting headaches and I really
struggle to see things that are far away.
But I've always had 2020 vision.
- Mm, sounds like you might be farsighted.
- Okay, then cover your left eye
and read the chart in front of you.
- Mm, X, E, R, three,
question mark, and I
can't quite make out the
other symbol, but I
think it's the peace sign.
- Well, Arthur, you're as blind as a bat.
- Yeah, I know.
- My vision is really blurry at times.
- Okay, then, head over to the other room
and pick out some frames
while I fill out your prescription.
- Thanks, dark.
Arthur, that's the bathroom.
- Well, this guy really
has poor vision, hey?
- Well, actually, you know what?
I've walked into the bathroom.
The men's bathroom actually
instead of the women's bathroom,
and that's not 'cause I
wasn't wearing my glasses.
Because you weren't paying attention.
- That's true.
- Okay, let's take a look today
at our language takeaway.
- Language takeaway.
- The first word on our language
takeaway for today is 2020 vision.
- 2020 vision.
- If I have 2020 vision, it means that you
have perfect vision, which I do not have.
- No, me neither, so I
usually wear glasses as well.
- Yeah, but yeah, people that
have 2020 vision don't need glasses.
They can see clearly and perfectly.
- And perfectly.
- Yeah.
- Next word is far sighted.
- Far sighted.
- So if I'm far sighted, I
can't see very well, right?
- So if you're far sighted, you
can see things that are near.
- So you can see things that are far away.
- Right.
- But things that are close are blurry.
- Okay.
- And the opposite would be.
- Near sighted.
- Which is, you can see
things that are close well.
- But not far.
- Yeah.
- Okay.
- Far sighted and near sighted.
- Okay, so our next word is make out.
- Make out.
That's kind of a funny little phrase.
And let's listen to a few examples of this
phrase so we can understand how it's used.
- Example one.
I can't make out what this says.
- The writing is too small.
- Example two.
- If you look carefully, you can almost
make out a few of the stars in the sky.
- Example three.
- Can you see what's
written on the sign there?
- No, I can't quite make it out.
- Okay, so basically
make out is to see clearly.
- Exactly.
- Make out.
- To see.
- Okay.
And our last word for language
takeaway today is blind as a bat.
- Blind as a bat.
- So this is a really funny
sounding expression.
One of these weird English idioms.
- Yeah, it's a really common expression
that just means that you can't see.
- Exactly.
So it's not like you
actually are blind, right?
- But you just really can't see very well.
- Okay, all right, we saw four great
words today in our language takeaway.
Now, I think we can listen
to our dialogue another time.
- But this time it's gonna
be slower so we can pick
up all these great words
that we just talked about.
(upbeat music)
- Hello Arthur, what
seems to be the problem?
- Very dark world.
I think I might need glasses.
I'm getting headaches and I really
struggle to see things that are far away.
- But I've always had 2020 vision.
- Sounds like you may be farsighted.
- Okay then, cover your left eye
and read the chart in front of you.
- Mm, it's E, R, three, a question mark
and I can't quite make up the other
symbol but I think it's a peace sign.
- Wow, Arthur, yours blind as a bat.
- Yeah, I know, my vision
is really blurry at times.
- Okay then, head on over to the other room
and pick out some frames
while I fill out your prescription.
- Thanks, dark.
- Arthur, that's the bathroom.
- All right, great stuff on our dialogue
and with this we can start
now with putting it together.
- Putting it together.
- So we saw a couple of
useful phrases in this dialogue
and I think we can show
you how to use these phrases
in a few different ways.
- Right, the first one that we
have today is what seems to be.
- So we heard in the dialogue the
doctor said, what seems to be the problem?
- We can use the same expression
in a number of different ways.
Let's listen.
- Example one, what
seems to be the problem?
- Example two.
- What seems to be the matter?
- Example three, what
seems to be a trouble?
- Okay, so with these
examples, we can see how we can
use the phrase what seems
to be in many different ways.
- Yeah, it's a great way of
asking, what's the problem?
So now let's take a look at another phrase.
We heard in the dialogue the doctor
said, head on over to the other room.
- Right, and with this phrase,
head on, we can combine
it with other prepositions
to indicate another place.
- Exactly, let's hear three examples.
- Example one.
- Head on in.
- Example two.
- Head on out.
- Example three.
- Head on up.
- Okay, so for example, we can say, head
on into the house, it's gonna rain soon.
Or we can say, hey guys,
let's head on out to the park.
- Mm-hmm.
- Or I can also say, head on up to
my room, I'll be there in a second.
- Great, those are some cool phrases.
- Right, and they're really useful.
- So why don't we listen to our
dialogue and maybe we'll hear them again?
(upbeat music)
- Hello Arthur, what
seems to be the problem?
- Hey dark, we're all, I
think I might need glasses.
I'm getting headaches and I really
struggle to see things that are far away.
- But I've always had 2020 vision.
- Sounds like you might be farsighted.
- Okay then, cover your left eye
and read the chart in front of you.
- Mm, X, E, R, three.
- Uh, question mark,
and I can't quite make out
the other symbol, but I
think it's the peace sign.
- Well, Arthur, yours blind is a bat.
- Yeah, I know, my vision
is really blurry at times.
- Okay then, head over to the other room
and pick out some frames
while I fill out your prescription.
- Thanks dark.
- Arthur, that's the bathroom.
- Okay, so talking about
going to the eye doctor
today, I have a
question for our listeners.
- A challenge for our listeners.
- What's it called when
you can't distinguish colors?
- So like when you can't tell the
difference between red and blue and green.
- Right, so what is that condition called?
- So there's like a technical term.
We want the technical term.
- We want the technical term.
So we'll be looking for
it on our comments page
and be sure to, if you
know the answer, post it.
- At EnglishPod.com.
Also if you have questions
about today's lesson
or any other lesson, please come
and visit our website and ask us.
- Yeah, we hope to see you
there, but until then, it's goodbye.
(upbeat music)